<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Responsi 1 Mobile (H1D023077)</string>
    <string name="team_name">Leeds United FC</string>
    <string name="leeds_summary">Leeds United is a professional football club from Leeds, England, famously known as "The Whites." The club boasts a glorious history, particularly under Don Revie in the 1960s and 70s when they were a dominant force in English and European football. Leeds are also renowned for their exceptionally passionate fanbase and their iconic home ground, Elland Road.</string>
    <string name="club_history">Club History</string>
    <string name="head_coach">Head Coach</string>
    <string name="team_squad">Team Squad</string>
    <string name="leeds_history">"Leeds United was founded in 1919, following the disbandment of Leeds City, the town's previous professional club, which was forcibly dissolved by The Football League for financial irregularities. The new club, Leeds United, was elected into the Football League's Second Division in 1920 and began to build its identity at their now-iconic home ground, Elland Road. The club's early years were a struggle, and they fluctuated between the First and Second Divisions without truly establishing themselves among the English elite.

The club's most defining and successful era began with the appointment of Don Revie as manager in 1961. Revie transformed Leeds into a footballing powerhouse, instilling a fierce team spirit and a highly disciplined, tactically astute style of play. Under his leadership, the "Revie Boys" won two First Division titles (1968-69, 1973-74), one FA Cup (1972), one League Cup (1968), and two Inter-Cities Fairs Cups (1968, 1971), establishing themselves as one of the best teams in Europe.

Following Revie's departure to manage the English national team in 1974, the club entered a period of gradual decline, despite a brief resurgence under Jimmy Armfield who led them to the European Cup final in 1975, where they lost to Bayern Munich. The following decades saw Leeds yo-yoing between divisions and struggling to recapture their former glory, with only minor cup successes to break the monotony. A low point came in 1982 when the club faced severe financial difficulties and were even relegated to the Second Division.

A dramatic and unexpected return to the summit of English football occurred under manager Howard Wilkinson in the early 1990s. Leeds won the Second Division in 1990 to gain promotion to the top flight and then, against all odds, captured the First Division title in 1992, the last season before the inception of the Premier League. This title victory, which broke the dominance of rivals Manchester United and Liverpool, marked a glorious, if brief, renaissance for the club.

Buoyed by the league title, Leeds embarked on an ambitious and ultimately disastrous strategy of spending large sums of borrowed money on transfer fees and wages in a bid to conquer Europe. This period saw them reach the UEFA Champions League semi-finals in 2001 with a talented, young squad featuring players like Rio Ferdinand, Alan Smith, and Mark Viduka. However, the failure to qualify for the Champions League the following season exposed the club's perilous financial fragility.

The financial bubble burst catastrophically in the early 2000s, leading to a fire sale of star players and, in 2004, relegation from the Premier League. The situation worsened dramatically as the club entered administration in 2007, incurring a massive points deduction that led to a second successive relegation, this time to the third tier of English football for the first time in their history. This period represented the darkest chapter for Leeds United, a stark contrast to the heights they had enjoyed just a few years prior.

Leeds spent over a decade in the Football League Championship and even League One, grappling with unstable ownership and a series of failed promotion attempts. A pivotal turning point arrived in 2018 with the appointment of the world-renowned Argentine coach Marcelo Bielsa, which ignited the club and its fanbase. Bielsa's transformative, high-intensity style of play, dubbed "Bielsa-ball," finally propelled Leeds back to the Premier League in 2020 after a 16-year absence, marking a glorious and emotional return to the top flight.

The club's long-awaited Premier League return has seen them re-establish themselves, though they were relegated again in 2023 after a three-season stay. The current era is defined by a continued pursuit of stability and a desire to once again compete at the highest level, with the goal of avoiding the financial excesses of the past. Throughout all its triumphs and tribulations, Leeds United has maintained one of English football's most passionate and loyal fanbases, whose unwavering support remains the club's greatest constant.

"</string>
    <string name="history_title">Leeds United FC History</string>
    <string name="loading">"Loading…"</string>

</resources>